RICHARD "RICK" ANSAY

Highlands Ranch, CO 80129

Phone: 720-273-9655 | Email: rick.ansay@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rick-ansay/ | GitHub: https://github.com/RickyRicer

Portfolio: https://rickyricer.github.io/reactPortfolio/

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a passion for delivering tangible value to customers through thoughtful design and feature implementation with clean, well-tested code. Technically flexible with a track record of picking up new languages and technologies on the job. Experience working with new projects and extending a variety of legacy codebases. Growth mindset, effective in both highly collaborative environments and independent deep dives with an eagerness for continued learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, Cascading Style Sheets3, HTML5, Solidity, SQL, NoSQL Applications: GitHub, MongoDb, MySQL,

Tools: Express, React, Node.js, Handlebars, JQuery, Bootstrap, GraphQL, TypeScript

PROJECTS

MoonBay | https://github.com/theresaqueryforthat/MoonBay

https://moonbay.herokuapp.com/

- App that utilizes the OpenSea API to interact with the Ethereum blockchain, a "WEB2" version of OpenSea. Users can create a login, save/favorite NFTs, and even purchase them through the link to OS!
- Roles: JSON Web Token Integration, Back-End routing, Front-End Framework and design, API integration
- Tools / languages: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, GraphQL

NamePassPro | https://github.com/theresaqueryforthat/NamePassPro

http://namepass.herokuapp.com

- App utilizing the randomword API, and custom random generator logic to create secure and unique usernames and passwords
- Roles: Back-End routing, Front-End Framework and design, Homepage design, SCRUM
- Tools / languages: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, GraphQL

EXPERIENCE

Consultant – Part Time Leonora LLC

2022 – Present Highlands Ranch, CO

Developer consultant for local marketing agency, assisting in paid media pixel/event setup and CRO adjustments, including API connections for client databases.

Intern - Part Time WhatIsTime.art

2022 – Present Highlands Ranch, CO

Ethereum based NFT community and art project, internship to learn more about blockchain integration and best practices. Run test transactions and mints on ethereum testnet.

Vehicle Acquisition Specialist McDonald Automotive Group

2015 – Present Littleton, CO

Working in a small team of 4-6 people, helped to create department and processes from the ground-up. Began with 5 stores, now running 14 used car departments, and led sales from 300 cars per month to over 600 per month currently. Constantly fast paced environment that is ever-changing, adaptability and flexibility have been some of the key skills utilized throughout this position.

 Placed in top 10 for Audi's "Twin Cup Challenge" a knowledge, brand history, and customer service experience test

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of Denver, Denver, CO A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Colorado State University: Fort Collins, CO

PASSIONS

Crypto/NFT | 3D Printing | Video Games | Star Wars/Marvel/DC | Bernese Mountain Dogs | Certified Scuba Diver